imagine we have a triangle with sides of
length a b and c and the angles across
from the sides are labeled capital a
capital B and capital c respectively
drop in altitude from the vertex where
angle a is to the side of length a and
label it h this altitude cuts the
triangle into two right triangles from
the first one we see that the sine of
angle b equals H divided by c as H is
the opposite side and C is the
hypotenuse from the other right triangle
we see that the sine of C is equal to H
divided by B as H is the opposite side
and B is the hypotenuse of this triangle
as H is part of both of these equations
we can see that H equals B times sine of
C and H equals c times sine of B
from this we see that b times the sine
of angle C equals c times the sine of
angle B dividing both quantities by B
times C we see that sine of angle C
divided by C is equal to the sine of
angle B divided by B
now we can do a similar thing for the
angles A and B but this time we have to
be a little more careful this time when
we try to drop an altitude from the
vertex at angle C we see that we get a
new triangle created outside the
original like this we can label this
altitude by H and note that the newly
created outside triangle has an angle of
measure 180 degrees minus a the
supplementary angle to a
from this newly created right triangle
here we see that the sine of angle B
must be the opposite side length H
divided by the hypotenuse a on the other
hand from the small right triangle
created here we see that the sine of 180
degrees minus a must equal the opposite
side H divided by the hypotenuse B
once again both of these equalities
involve the quantity H so we see that H
is equal to B times the sine of 180
minus a and H equals a times the sine of
angle B
we can divide both of these quantities
by a times B so that sine of 180 degrees
minus a over a is equal to sine of angle
B divided by little B but now we use the
fact that sine of 180 degrees minus a is
equal to the sine of angle a this means
that the sine of angle a divided by side
length a is equal to the sine of angle B
divided by the side length little B when
we couple this result with our first
computation we see that the sine of
angle a divided by a equals the sine of
angle B divided by B and that equals the
sine of angle C divided by C where a B
and C are the side lengths of a triangle
with opposite angles capital a capital b
capital c respectively this is known as
The Law of Sines for triangles